visionsfcu.org 2006-10-04

# Welcome to VisionLine

**Visions Federal Credit Union Privacy Notice and Disclosure**

Visions Federal Credit Union is owned by its members and run by a board of directors you elect. At Visions we value your membership and your privacy. You can be confident that your financial privacy and safeguarding your personal information is a top priority of this credit union. We are required by law to give you this privacy notice annually to explain how we and our affiliate, Visions Agency LLC, collect, use and safeguard your personal financial information. If you have any questions, please call a Member Service Representative at 607-754-7900 or 800-242-2120. Or you may write us at : 

Privacy Coordinator  
Visions Federal Credit Union  
24 McKinley Avenue  
Endicott, NY 13760-5491 

We are committed to providing you with competitive products and services to meet your financial needs. This requires that we share information about you with our affiliate and also non-affiliated third party service providers who provide data processing, administrative and other types of support services. We may also disclose information about you under other circumstances as permitted or required by law. These disclosures typically include information necessary to follow your authorized instructions, to conduct the operations of the Credit Union or to protect the security of our financial records. This Privacy Notice Disclosure and the practices it describes are applicable to both Visions Federal Credit Union and its affiliate, the Visions Agency LLC.

**Information We Collect**

We collect nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources:

  * Membership and loan applications and other forms which you complete.
  * Your transactions with us, our affiliate, or other companies that work closely with us to provide you with financial products and services.
  * Consumer reporting agencies.
  * Current or past employers, other financial institutions and other sources, to verify information you provide on applications and other forms.
  * Information about your visits to our website (such as data provided through on-line forms, site visitor data, and security devices known as cookies).
  * Information to verify your identity as required by law.

**Information We Disclose**

We and our affiliate work closely to offer various financial services, products and other services to meet member needs. In order to do this , we may share your nonpublic, personal information with each other, as permitted by law. Further, we may disclose information we collect to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. We may also disclose nonpublic, personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties as permitted by law, such as check printers, credit reporting agencies, and government agencies. We do not disclose any nonpublic, personal information about former members to anyone, except as permitted by law.

**How We Protect Your Information**

To protect our members privacy, we work only with companies that agree to maintain confidentiality protections and which limit the use of information we provide to credit union approved purposes. These companies are not permitted to sell to other third parties the information provided. We also restrict access to nonpublic personal information about you to those credit union employees and official volunteers who have specific business purpose to use your data in order to provide financial services to you. Our policies strictly enforce standards to prevent any abuse of confidential information by limiting employee access and by educating our employees on confidentiality. We also maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations and leading industry practices to safeguard your nonpublic personal information, to include third-party testing or review of our systems.

**How You Can Help Protect Your Information**

  * Report lost/stolen checks, credit cards, or ATM cards to us immediately.
  * Keep your ATM, Check Card, PAT, or VisionLine PIN number(s) in a safe place and never disclose it to anyone, even our employees.
  * Keep your checks, ATM cards and credit cards in a safe place under your control at all times.
  * Protect your receipts and statements and destroy confidential information before placing them in the trash where they can be retrieved by another person.
  * Never disclose your personal account numbers or personal information on the telephone unless you are certain you are speaking with a credit union employee. If you are in doubt, request the name and telephone number of the caller and say that you will call them back.
  * Be aware of Internet “phishing” scams, that make it appear that a trusted source (your financial institution, a travel service, shopping site, bill payment, etc.) is asking you to verify your confidential account number and PIN or password in order to not have your account deactivated. For more information on this, visit our CU Information Center, Security/Identity Theft, at [http://www.visionsfcu.org](http://www.visionsfcu.org/)
